<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications on Academic</title>
    <link>/publication/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publications on Academic</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="/publication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting intention to receive a seasonal influenza vaccination using Protection Motivation Theory</title>
      <link>/publication/ling_etal_2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ling_etal_2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Systematic review of meditation-based interventions for children with ADHD</title>
      <link>/publication/evans_etal_2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/evans_etal_2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Validation of a Novel Climate Change Denial Measure Using Item Response Theory</title>
      <link>/publication/loram_etal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/loram_etal/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dissociation between wanting and liking for alcohol and caffeine: A test of the Incentive Sensitisation Theory</title>
      <link>/publication/arulkadacham_etal_2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/arulkadacham_etal_2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitigation system threat partially mediates the effects of right-wing ideologies on climate change beliefs</title>
      <link>/publication/clarke_etal_2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/clarke_etal_2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regression tree analysis of ecological momentary assessment data</title>
      <link>/publication/richardson_etal_2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/richardson_etal_2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Schizotypal Personality Questionnaire-Brief lacks measurement invariance across three countries</title>
      <link>/publication/liu_etal_2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/liu_etal_2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measurement and characterisation of individual differences in need for cognition.</title>
      <link>/publication/ling_2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ling_2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Need for Cognition (NFC) is a widely utilised construct in the psychological
literature, however the construct itself is poorly understood. While the progenitors of the
widely utilised self-report scale describe the construct as reflecting individual differences in
the tendency to engage in and enjoy effortful cognition, there is no consensus on the specific
motivation underpinning these differences. A clear model of this individual difference would
allow for accurate prediction of the conditions under which this tendency is most strongly
manifest, but also how it might be promoted. This thesis seeks to develop a more complete
representation of what it is to vary in NFC though systematic review of the literature
regarding the NFC scale’s dimensionality; empirical evaluation of the factorial structure of
the NFC scale in two samples; and examination of the proximate behavioural products of
NFC in both lab settings and ecological contexts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through evaluation of the literature it was found that while the measure is generally
treated as unidimensional, there is a trend for studies using true factor analysis methodologies
finding multifactorial solutions. However, within studies using these, no consistent factorial
solution was found, possibly due to methodological variation between these studies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To address this, factor analysis was conducted on the full-length scale in two
independent samples using consistent methodology. As such, consistency (or lack thereof) in
the factorial solutions derived in the two samples should reflect either the presence of
replicable factors or demonstrate that previously observed multifactorial solutions are a
function of incomplete optimisation of the NFC scale. Results favoured the latter, suggesting
that there is one replicable factor in the NFC scale reflecting tendency to engage in effortful
cognition; this duly did not provide insight into the drivers of this behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further insight into the motivation underpinning NFC was sought, specifically
evaluating the model of NFC as differences in enjoyment of the process of effortful cognition. In a controlled (lab) setting, NFC was shown to not be associated with either the
persistence with puzzle tasks or enjoyment of educational videos, suggesting that the impact
of NFC on engagement might not be as universal as would be expected if it indexed the
degree to which effortful cognition was intrinsically enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To obtain a better understanding of NFC outside of lab settings, an Ecological
Momentary Assessment (EMA) study was undertaken, examining the frequency and quality
of engagement in effortful cognition in real-world contexts. This further permitted the
validation of the prior study’s findings. The results of this study show that the NFC scale
predicts engagement in effortful cognition in ecological settings, but none of the enjoyment
thereof, effort invested, or the attribution to internal causes, despite there being individual
differences in tendency for these latter outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This program of research therefore is able to conclude that the 18-item short form
scale is better considered as an optimised measure, where the longer measures are liable to
include additional error. Further, while individual differences exist in the tendency to engage
in effortful cognition, the enjoyment thereof, as well as the investment of effort and
attribution bias for this engagement, the NFC scale only predicts engagement. While these
results particularly do not support the enjoyment of process account of intrinsic motivation in
NFC, more broadly they suggest that differences in behaviour associated with NFC may be
driven by both intrinsic and extrinsic motivations. Potential avenues for promoting effortful
cognition remain through the increased exposure to complex cognitive tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The use of the SDQ with Chinese adolescents in the clinical context</title>
      <link>/publication/mellor_etal_2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/mellor_etal_2016/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
